At the far ends of the earth she found a reason to
live, and a cause to fight for.
Gorillas in the Mist is a drama, history film directed by Michael Apted.
The story of Dian Fossey, a scientist who came to Africa to study the
vanishing mountain gorillas, and later fought to protect them.
Dian Fossey, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Bob Campbell, played by Bryan Brown.
Roz Carr, played by Julie Harris.
Sembagare, played by John Omirah Miluwi.
Dr. Louis Leakey, played by Iain Cuthbertson.
Claude Van Veeten, played by Konstantin Aleksandrov.
Gorillas in the Mist is a 1988 American biographical drama film directed by Michael Apted
from a screenplay by Anna Hamilton Phelan and a story by Phelan and Tab Murphy.
The film is based on a book of the same name by Dian
Fossey and from articles by Harold T.
Hayes, and Alex Shoumatoff of Vanity Fair.
It stars Sigourney Weaver as naturalist Dian Fossey and
Bryan Brown as photographer Bob Campbell.
It tells the story of Fossey, who came to Africa to study the vanishing
mountain gorillas, and later fought to protect them.
The film was theatrically released in the United States by
Universal Pictures on September 23, 1988.
At the 61st Academy Awards, it earned five nominations, including Best Actress for
Weaver and Best Writing, Screenplay Based on Material from Another Medium.
The film won Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Drama for Weaver and Best Original Score for Jarre at the
46th Golden Globe Awards, where it was also nominated for Best Motion Picture – Drama.
The film explores themes of photographer, africa, rwanda, gorilla, menace.
The tone is emotional.